A Guide to the Papers of Howard W. Smith, 1933-1966
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series II: Miscellaneous Legislation
  - Subseries G - 84th Congress
    - H.R. 3 - hearings before Sub-committee No. 1 - Committee on the Judiciary establishing rules of interpretation governing questions of the effect of acts of Congress upon state laws. (Box 84)
    - H.R. 462-hearings of the committee on rules. Proposed establishment of Committee on Administrative Procedure and Practice (Box 84)
    - H.R. 3 - to establish rules of interpretation governing questions of the effect of acts of Congress upon state laws (Box 84)
    - H.R. 11922-bill to amend D.C. Alcoholic Beverage Control Act of 1934 (Box 84)
    - H.R. 192-bill to amend P.L. 526 of 79th Congress, section 10 of Flood Control Act, July 24, 1946 (Rappanahock River) (Box 84)
    - H.R. 627-act to provide means of further securing and protecting civil rights of persons within the jurisdiction of the United States (Box 84)
    - Copy of letter, Southern Congressmen to President Eisenhower, July 12, 1957; re: Voting Rights (Box 85)
    - H.R. 7217-to provide revenue for the District of Columbia and for other purposes (Box 85)
    - H.R. 8168-to provide revenue for the District of Columbia and for other purposes (Box 85)
    - H.R. 3 - report from the Committee of the Juriscary amending title 18 of the U.S. Code to authorize the enforcement of state statutes prescribing Criminal penalties for Subversive activities (Box 85)
    - H.R. 3 -hearings before sub-committee No. 1 - House of Representatives (Box 85)
    - H.R. 627-hearings before the Committee on Rules - House of Representatives (Box 85)
    - H.R. 462-hearings before a special committee of the Committee on Administrative Procedure and Practice; investigation of public school conditions (Box 85)
    - Remarks from Congr. Record-84th Congress (Box 85)
  - Subseries B-85th Congress - 1st Session
    - H.R. 119-resolution amending clause 1-Rule 10 of the Rules of the House of Representatives (Box 85)
    - H. Joint R. 421-designating the year 1958 as the James Monroe Bicentennial Year and creating a commission to supervise and direct the observance of such year (Box 85)
  - Subseries B-85th Congress - 2nd Session
    - H.R. 646-resolution to amend House Rules re: withdrawal of money from the Treasury (Box 85)
    - H.R. 3 -bill to establish rules of interpretation governing questions of the effect of Acts of Congress on State Laws (Box 85)
    - H.R. 1151-to provide an additional Assistant Attorney General to establish a bi-partisan commission on civil rights of the executive branch of the government and to provide means of further securing and protecting the right to vote to strengthen the Civil rights statutes and for other purposes (Box 85)
    - H.R. 2509-to amend the Alcoholic Beverage Control Act of the District of Columbia of 1934 (Box 85)
    - H.R. 3413-bill to improve and extend, through reciprocal legislation, the enforcement of duties of support in D.C. (Box 85)
    - Hearings of the Committee on Un-American Activities, July 29-31, 1958- Communist Infiltration and Activities in the South (Box 85)
    - H.R. 4836-to provide for examination, licensing and regulation of dispensing opticians and optical technicians of the District of Columbia and for other purposes (Box 85)
    - H.R. 5498-to amend the act of June 29, 1938 to increase the amount of the bond or insurance for the protection of passengers required of cabs for hire in D.C. (Box 85)
    - H.R. 5965-to improve and extend through reciprocal legislation the enforcement of duties of support in the District of Columbia, (see H.R. 3413) (Box 85)
    - H.R. 5966-to amend the act entitled "An Act to Regulate the Practice of Optometry in the District of Columbia." (Box 85)
    - H.R. 6127-Civil Rights Act of 1957. Copy of House Bill as reported to the Senate (Box 85)
    - H.R. 7104-to amend the District of Columbia income and franchise tax act of 1947 by providing an additional personal exemption for resident income tax payers and their spouses who are blind. (Box 85)
    - H.R. 7248-to amend the District of Columbia income and franchise tax act of 1947 to provide that under certain conditions officers of the executive branch of the federal government appointed by the President shall be exempt from such act. (Box 85)
    - H.R. 7249-to improve and extend through reciprocal legislation the enforcement of duties of support in the District of Columbia (Box 85)
    - H.R. 7467-an act to amend the act of March 3, 1901, with respect to citizenship and residence qualifications of the Director or Trustees of certain companies in the District of Columbia (Box 85)
    - H.R. 7467-an act to amend the act of March 3, 1901, with respect to citizenship and residence qualifications of the Director or Trustees of certain companies in the District of Columbia (Box 85)
    - H.R. 7835-a bill to increase the authorization for appropriations for the hospital center and facilities in the District of Columbia and for other purposes. (Box 85)
    - Report 587 [to accompany H.R. 7835] - increasing the authorization for appropriations for the hospital center and facilities in the District of Columbia (Box 85)
    - H.R. 8256-a bill to amend the District of Columbia income and franchise tax act of 1947 (Box 85)
    - H.R. 8361-a bill to amend section 2254 of Title 28 of the United States Code (Box 85)
    - H.R. 8918-a bill to further amend the act of August 7, 1947, D.C. hospitals (Box 85)
    - H.R. 9271 [Private Law 85-554] - an act to authorize the National Society of the Sons of the American Revolution to use ceratain real estate in the District of Columbia as the national headquarters of such society (Box 85)
    - H.R. 11102 [P.L. 85-554] - an act amending the jurisdiction of District courts in civil actions with regard to the amount in controversy and diversity of citizenship. (Box 85)
    - H.R. 12377-a bill to authorize the commissioners of the District of Columbia to borrow funds for capital improvement programs and to amend provisions of law relating to federal government participation in meeting costs of maintaining the nation's capital city (Box 85)
    - H.R. 12969-a bill to authorize the delivery of sewage from Virginia into the sewage system of the District of Columbia and the treatment of such sewage, and for other purposes (Box 85)
    - H.R. 13408-a bill to amend section 34041 of Title 18 of the United States Code (Box 85)
    - H.R. 13628-a bill to amend section 2(b)(5), Title 3 of the District of Columbia income franchise act of 1947, as amended, and for other purposes (Box 85)
    - Congressional Record s-85th Congress-1st session, June 6-June 11, 1957. A compleete set of the civil rights debates of those days. (Box 85)
    - Congressional Record -85th Congress-2nd Session, July 15, 16, 17, 1958; August 19, 20, 21, 1958. A compleete set of the records with debate on H.R. 3-both house and senate. (Box 86)
    - Congressional Record -85th Congress-1st session, June 13, 14, 17, 18; August 27, 1957. Judge Smith's remarks on civil rights (Box 86)
    - Reports and studies relating to civil rights legislation (Box 87)
    - Report 291 [to accompany H.R. 2617] - committee on the Judiciary, favorable report on proposed civil rights bill. (Box 87)
    - Hearings before the Committee on Un-American Activities of the House of Representatives-July 29, 30, 31, 1958 (Box 87)
    - Communist infiltration and activities in the South (Box 87)
    - Report 1878 [to accompany H.R. 3] - establishing rules of interpretation for federal courts involving the doctrine of federal preemption (Box 87)
    - Hearings before the Committee on Un-American Activities of the Judiciary on H.R. 3, May 13 and 20, 1958. Establishing rules of interpretation governing questions of the effect of the acts of Congress on state laws. (Box 87)
    - P.L. 85-199 [H.R. 7467] - to amend Act of March 3, 1901 re D.C. residence and citizenship of directors of companies (Box 87)
    - Hearing before the Committee on the District of Columbia on H.R. 2510. To amend the Alcholic Beverage Control Act of the District of Columbia of 1934, as amended. (Box 87)
    - H.R. 6127 [P.L. 85-315]-an act to provide means of further securing and protecting the civil rights of persons within the jurisdiction of the United States (Box 87)
    - Staff Report prepared for the Joint Committee on Washington Metropolitan Problems on Conservation and Recreation in a Comprehensive Program for the Potomac River Basin with special reference to the National Capitaal region. Metropolitan Water Problems. (Box 87)
    - Staff Report prepared for the Joint Committee on Washington Metropolitan Problems on Sewage Disposal and Water Pollution in the Washington Metropolitan Area. Sewage Disposal and Water Pollution. (Box 87)
    - Staff Report prepared for the Joint Committee on Washington Metropolitan Problems on Water Supply in Washington Metropolitan area. Water Supply (Box 87)
    - Hearings before the Special Investigation Committee on the House Committee on H.R. 251. To investigate the public works program, the revenue act, and the public health service of the District of Columbia. (Box 87)
    - Hearings before the Joint Committee on Washington Metropolitan Problems. Washington Metropolitan area transportation problems. (Box 87)
    - Hearings before the Committee on Rules on H.R. 6127. Civil rights. (Box 87)
    - Public Law 85-94 [H.R. 7249] - to extend duties of support on D.C. (Box 87)
    - Public Law 85-281 [H.R. 8256] - act to amend D.C. Income and Franchise Act of 1947 (Box 87)
    - Hearings before the Sub-Committee on Constitutional Rights of the Committee on the Judiciary. Civil Rights 1957. (Box 87)
    - Staff study for the Joint Committee on Washington Metropolitan Problems. A metropolitan statistical program for the National Capital region. (Box 87)
    - Statement by Representative Howard W. Smith of Virginia. Is the purpose, federal aid to education or federal control of education? (Box 87)
    - Staff study for the Joint Committee on Washington Metropolitan Problems. The governing of Metropolitan Washington. (Box 87)
    - Minority report from the Sub-committee on Constitutional Rights. Civil rights [to accompany S. 83]. (Box 87)
    - Sub-Committee on Constitutional Rights Report [to accompany S. 83]. Civil rights. (Box 87)
    - Final report of the Special Committee. Special committee to investigate political activities, lobbying, and campaign contributions. (Box 87)
    - Report of the anti-trust sub-committee on the committee on the Judiciary regarding H.R. 107 on the Television Broadcasting Industry. (Box 87)
    - Summary of proposed amendments to the Constitution of the United States introduced in Congress from the 69th Congress, 2nd Session through the 84th Congress, 2nd Session (Box 87)
    - Hearings before the Special Investigation Sub-Committee of the House Committee on the District of Columbia on H.R. 251. Part 2. To investigate the public works program, the revenue act, and the public health service of the District of Columbia. (Box 87)
    - Report 525 [H.R. 7249] - to extend duties of support in D.C. (Box 87)
    - Report 587 [H.R. 7835] - to increase appropriations for hospitals in D.C. (Box 87)
    - Hearings before the Committee on Rules - House of Representatives on H.R. 6127. Civil rights (Box 87)
    - Hearings before Sub-Committee No. 5 of the Committee on the Judiciary. Civil Rights. (Box 87)
  - 86th Congress. Hearings and Reports
    - Hearings before Sub-Committee No. 3 of the Committee on the Judiciary. Habeas Corpus. (Box 87)
    - Report on U.S. Foreign Aid. Prepared by legislative reference service, Library of Congress. (Box 87)
    - Report [to accompany H.R. 7681] - enacting the provisions of reorganization plan no. 1 of 1959 with certain provisions. (Box 87)
    - Staff report prepared for the Joint Committee on Washington Metropolitan Problems. A discussion guide to Washington area metropolitan problems. (Box 87)
    - Public Law 86-669. H.R. 11135-an act to aid in the development of a coordinated system of transportation for the National Capital region. (Box 87)
    - Report of the Joint Committee on Washington Metropolitan Problems. Washington Metropolitan Problems, Progress and Prospects. (Box 87)
  - 87th Congress. Acts, Bills, Hearings, Reports, Etc.
    - H.R. 3 - a bill to establish rules of interpretation governing questions of the effect of acts of Congress on state laws. (Box 87)
    - Joint Resolution 121 - to amend the Constitution of the United States to guarantee the right of any state to apportion one house of its legislature on factors other than population. (Box 88)
    - H.R. 3092 - a bill to amend section 1332 (c) of Title 28 of the United States Code, relating to the diversity of citizenship. (Box 88)
    - H.R. 3093-a bill to amend section 2254 of Title 28 of the United States Code. (Box 88)
    - H.R. 3094-a bill to amend section 3401 of Title 18, of the United States Code. (Box 88)
    - Public Law 87-30 [H.R. 3935] - an act to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938. (Box 88)
    - Hearings before Sub-Committee No. 3 of the Committee on the Judiciary. Increasing the membership of the House of Representatives and redistricting congressional districts. (Box 88)
    - Hearing before Sub-Committee No. 3 of the Committee on the Judiciary. Establishing rules of interpretation governing questions of the effect of acts of Congress on state laws. (Box 88)
    - H.R. 10650-a bill to amend the internal revenue code of 1954 to provide a credit for investments in certain depreciable property, to eliminate certain defects in equities, and for other purposes. (Box 88)
    - Report of the Committee on Ways and Means. Revenue Act of 1962. (Box 88)
    - Committee on Education and Labor. A directory of federally financed student loans, fellowships, and career training programs in the field of higher education in the United States. (Box 88)
    - Report [to accompany H.R. 3] - establishing rules of interpretation for federal courts involving the doctrine of federal premption. (Box 88)
    - Hearings before the Sub-committee on Election of the Committee on House Administration. Proposed amendment to the Hatch Political Activities Act. (Box 88)
    - P.L. 87-792 - an act to encourage the establishment of voluntary pension plan by self-employed individuals. (Box 88)
    - P.L. 87-793 [H.R. 7927] - an act to adjust postal rates and for other purposes. (Box 88)
    - Congressional Record - 87th Congress, 1st and 2nd Sessions (Box 88)
    - Excerpts of speeches made by Judge Smith regarding financial matters and subjects such as, peace corps, public works, atomic energy commission, authorization, etc. (Box 88)
    - Letter-Rosalie C. Smith. July 5, 1961. Regarding support for Judge Smith's position on United Nations appropriations (Box 88)
    - Congressional Record -June 22-July 2, 1959 (Box 89)
  - 86th Congress
    - S. 3 - a bill to establish rules of interpretation governing questions of the effects of acts of Congress on state laws. (Box 90)
    - H.R. 3216 - a bill to amend section 2254 of Title 28 of the United States Code (Box 90)
    - H.R. 3216 [Report W 548] - Committee on the Judiciary. Habeas Corpus (Box 90)
    - H.R. 3217 - a bill to amend section 1332(c) of Title 28 of the United States Code (Box 90)
    - H.R. 3218 - a bill to amend section 3401 of Title 18, of the United Stated Code (Box 90)
    - H.R. 8912 - a bill to amend section 1332 (c ) of Title 28 of the United States Code relating to the diversity of citizenship. (Box 90)
    - Federal Register, November 24, 1962-Executive Order 11063. Equal opportunity in housing. (Box 90)
    - Hearings before the Special Sub-Committee on Radiation of the Joint Committee on Atomic Energy. Biological and environmental effects of nuclear war. (Box 90)
  - 87th Congress
    - H.R. 3 - [Report W 1820] - establishing rules of interpretation for Federal Courts re Federal pre-emption (Box 90)
    - H.R. 3 - hearing before Sub-committee No. 3 - Judiciary Committee (Box 90)
    - Hearings before the Sub-committee on Appropriations, Part 2. (Box 90)
    - District of Columbia Appropriations for 1963 (Box 90)
    - Congressional Record - January 31, 1961 (Box 90)
  - 88th Congress. Bills and Reports (Box 90)
    - H.R. 405 - a bill to prohibit discrimination in employment (Box 90)
    - H.R. 3- a bill to establish rules of interpretation governing questions of the effect of acts of Congress on state laws. (Box 90)
    - H.R. 97 - a resolution to amend the rules of the House of Representatives (Box 90)
    - H.R. 7300-Report School Assistant Act of 1961 (Box 90)
    - H.R. 106-a resolution to amend the rules of the House of Representatives (Box 90)
    - H. Joint R. 123-joint resolution to authorize the achitect of the Capital to construct a memorial to James Madison (Box 90)
    - H.R. 1833-a bill to amend section 3401 of Title 18 of the United States Code. (Box 90)
    - H.R. 1835-a bill to amend section 2254 of Title 28 of the United States Code (Box 90)
    - H.R. 7152-Civil and Voting Rights (Box 90)
    - Message from the President of the United States relative to Civil Rights. (Box 90)
    - H. Joint R. 1181 - memorializing Dr. Mahlon Loomis. (Box 90)
    - Hearings before the Committee on Rules on H.R. 789. Civil Rights. (Box 90)
    - H.R. 7152 - proposed Civil Rights Act of 1963 (Box 90)
    - Minority report upon Proposed Civil Rights Act of 1963. Committee on Judiciary Substitute for H.R. 7152. (Box 90)
    - Report [H.R. 11377] - Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 (Box 90)
    - Senate Bill 1731 - Right to vote (Box 90)
    - Senate Bill 1732 - Public accomodations (Box 90)
    - Compilation of material for use in connection with report on full Committee substitute for H.R. 7152. (Box 90)
  - 88th Congress. Hearings and Reports
    - P.L. 88-452 [S. 2642] to combat poverty in United States (Box 91)
    - Hearings before Sub-Committee No. 6 of the Committee on the District of Columbia. Crime legislation for the District of Columbia (Box 91)
    - Hearings before the Select Committee on Government Research. Federal Research and Development Programs. Parts 1 and 2 (Box 91)
    - Report [to accompany H.R. 7152] - Civil Rights Act of 1963 (Box 91)
    - Hearings before the Committee on Rules on H.R. 7152-Civil Rights-Part 2 (Box 91)
    - First Progress Report on the Select Committee on Government Research. Federal Research and Development Programs (Box 91)
    - Hearings before the Committee on Rules on H.R. 789. Civil Rights. (Box 91)
    - Report of the Select Committee on Government Research - 10 studies: (Box 91)
      Study#1. Administration of Research and Development Grants. Study#2. Manpower for Research and Development. Study#3. Federal facilities for Research and Development. Study #4. Documentation and dissemination of Research and Development Results. Study#5. Federal Student Assistants in Federal Education. Study #6. Impact of Federal Research and Development Programs. Study#7. Contract policies and procedures for Research and Development Study#8. Inter-Agency Coordinator in Research and Development. Study#9. Statistical Review of Research and Development. Study#10. National Goals and Policies
  - 78th Congress -H.R. 102-Hearings before the Special Committee to investigate executive agencies (Box 91)
    - H.R. 102 - intermediate reports 1-3, 5-7. (Box 91)
  - 79th Congress -H.R. 102 - Intermediate Reports 8 & 9 (Box 91)
    - H.R. 88 - hearings re executive agencies #1-5 (Box 91)
  - 89th Congress - Economic Division of the Legislation Reference Service Library of Congress, compiler. National Labor Policy. The Public Interest in Labor-Management Relations. (Box 91)
  - 89th Congress - 1st Session (Box 91)
    - H. Joint R. 685-memoralizing Dr. Mahlon Loomis (Box 91)
  - 89th Congress - 2nd Session (Box 92)
    - H. Joint R. 1164 - to amend D.C. Metropolitan Transit Compact to provide transit facilities (Box 92)
    - H.R. 15645 - bill to exclude moving expenses from income tax (Box 92)
  - 88th Congress-2nd Session (Box 92)
    - H.R. 1835 - to amend U.S. Code re: habeas corpus writs (Box 92)
    - Congressional Record s (Box 92)
  - 88th Congress-1st Session - Jan. 9, 1963 (Box 92)
  - 88th Congress - 2nd Session - Jan. 31; Feb. 1; Feb. 3-6; Feb. 8; Feb. 10; July 2; Sept. 21; Sept. 27. (Box 92)
  - 89th Congress - 1st Session - Cong. Record - speech, April 13, 1965, "What's Behind the So-Called Negro Revolution?" (Box 92)
  - 89th Congress - 2nd Session - Cong. Record - speech, June 28, 1966, "Communist Party Reorganized in Violation f Smith Act" (Box 92)
  - 88th Congress - 1st Session - Cong. Record - speech, May 8, 1963, "Massive Federal Spending and Concentration of Power" (Box 92)
    speech, Sept. 25, 1963, "Folly of Reduction in Taxes with Increased Spending"
  - 88th Congress - 2nd Session - Cong. Record - speech, Aug. 19, 1964, "Reapportionment of State Legislatures - Supreme Court Assumes Unauthorized Power to Write the Laws of the States" (Box 92)
  - Folder-Correspondence re: Post Office, Chancellor, Va., 1953-1966 (Box 93)
  - Folder-Correspondence re: G.S.H. Lands for recreational purposes, 1965 (Box 93)
  - Folder-Report re: zoning for low cost housing in Arlington, Va., 1965 (Box 93)
  - Folder-Documents re: Va.-Md. Potomac River Boundary - 1928 (Box 93)
    Correspondence re: endorsements, 1966
  - Folder-Correspondence and documents re: creation of recreational facilities of Mason Neck, 1966 (Box 93)
  - Miscellaneous Papers and Documents
    - Editorial - The National Republic, Aug. 1940 re: Smith (Box 93)
    - News release and copy - Smith's speech of Dec. 18, 1939 re: N.L.R.B. (Box 93)
    - Undated news release: Smith receives honors from Investors Union of America (Box 93)
    - Copy of J.F.K.'s Special Message on Balance of Payments, July 18, 1963 (Box 93)
    - Tape and printed copy of Smith's interview on Meet the Press, Jan. 26, 1964 (Box 93)
    - Copy of First Annual Report. Supreme Allied Commander Europe, April 2, 1952 (Box 93)
    - Copy of The Democratic Platform, Aug. 15, 1956 (Box 93)
  - 84th Congress - 2nd Session
    - Report of Committee on Public Works re: H.R. 9540 re: Water Pollution Control Act (Box 93)
    - H.R. 9540-to extend Water Pollution Control Act (Box 93)
  - 89th Congress-2nd Session (Box 93)
    - Report of Joint Committee re: Organization of Congress (Box 93)
    - Report of Committee on Education & Labor re: H.R. 13161 re: Elementary and Secondary Education Amendments of 1966 (Box 93)
    - Supplemental Report on Elementary and Secondary Education Amendments of 1966. (Box 93)
    - H.R. 13161-bill to improve aid to education (Box 93)
    - H.R. 15111-hearings on Economic Opportunity Act Amendments of 1966 (Box 93)
    - Report No. 1414 (Final Report) - Organization of Congress (Box 93)
    - Supreme Court Decisions (Box 93)
      - No. 10 - Oct. Term, 1955 (Box 93)
        Penna. Vs. Reed
      - No. 584-Oct. Term, 1958 (Box 93)
        Lassiter vs. Northampton County Board of Elections
      - No. 35-Oct. Term, 1958 (Box 93)
        Barenblatt vs. U.S.A.
      - H.R. 13712-hearings on Minimum Wage (Box 93)
      - H.R. 14544 & S. 2499 - Hearings - Private Financing of Credit Needs to amend Small Business Act (Box 93)
    - Supreme Court Decisions
      - Oct. Term 1963 - Civil Rights and Apportionment (Box 93)
      - No. 22-Wesberry vs. Sanders (Box 93)
      - No. 20-W.M.C.A. Inc. vs. Lorenzo (Box 93)
      - No. 23-Reynolds vs. Sims (Box 93)
      - No. 27-Vann & Vance vs. Baggett (Box 93)
      - No. 41-McConnell vs. Baggett (Box 93)
      - No. 29-Md. Comm. For Fair Representation vs. (Box 93)
      - No. 69-Davis vs. Mann (Box 93)
      - No. 508-Lucas vs. General Assembly of Colorado (Box 93)
  - Housing Legislation - 89th Congress (Box 94)